Finding Aid for Campbell Bonner papers, 1886-1954
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Campbell Bonner papers 1886-1954 1918-1954
Bonner, Campbell, b. 1876.
1.5 linear feet
85474 Aa 2
Professor of Greek language and literature at the University of Michigan. Family and professional correspondence, diaries, notebooks discussing travels and readings, manuscripts of articles, and miscellanea; miscellaneous papers of his wife, Ethel Bonner, and assorted diaries of family members; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were transferred from the University Museum (donor no. 837 ); additional materials came from Ralph and Lydia Muncy (donor no. 4010 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Campbell Bonner was born in Nashville, Tennessee, on January 30, 1876. He received his bachelor's degree from Vanderbilt University in 1896, and his A.M. (1898) and Ph.D. (1900) from Harvard.
In 1900, he went to the University of Berlin, spent some time in Greece and Italy, and returned to the U.S. in 1901 to become professor of Greek at Peabody College for Teachers in Nashville, Tennessee. Bonner came to the University of Michigan in 1907 as junior professor of Greek. He became full professor in 1912 and in 1932, he was selected chairman of the Greek department.
Bonner was the author of "A Papyrus Codix of the Shepherd of Hermas," "The Last Chapters of Enoch in Greek," and "Homily on the Passion by Melito, Bishop of Sardis." He was also a frequent contributor on classical philology, papyrology and history of religions.
He was a member of the American Philological Association and its president in 1933; the Classical Association, Middle West and South (president, 1918-1919); the Archaeological Institute of America; Michigan Academy of Science, Arts and Letters (president, 1923-1924); a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences; corresponding fellow of the British Academy; the American Philosophical Society; the managing committee of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens, annual professor, 1927-1928; and Phi Beta Kappa.
He died on Monday, July 12, 1954.
The Bonner collection consists of correspondence, subject files, writings, professional papers, and photographs. There are also diaries and other papers of his wife Ethel Bonner.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Classical Studies.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Anniversaries.; Archaeology.; Bonner, Campbell, b. 1876.; Bonner, Ethel H.; Sanders, Henry A. (Henry Arthur), 1868-1956.; Travel.; White, Alfred.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - Fragmentary (Box 1)
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1886 and 1900-1908 (Box 1)
  - 1918-1954, 23 folders (Box 1)
- Other papers
  - American School of Classical Studies, 1921-1924 (Box 1)
  - Papers relating to University faculty cutback, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
  - Reports on papyri, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Near East research committee minutes, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Publications and manuscripts of writings, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous writings (Box 1)
  - Membership in professional organizations (Box 1)
  - Henry Russel Lecturer, 1954 Certificate (Box 1)
  - Passport, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Notes, 1928 European trip (Box 1)
  - Reading notes, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Poems, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1919, concerning Jackson mummy (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Friends and family (Box 1)
    - Study and travel (Box 1)
    - Golden wedding celebration of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred White (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Photograph Album (Box 1)
- Ethel Bonner papers
  - Ethel Bonner, miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1918-1966, 10 volumes (Box 2)